<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fortran on Ondřej Čertík</title>
    <link>https://ondrejcertik.com/tags/fortran/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fortran on Ondřej Čertík</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ondrejcertik.com/tags/fortran/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>LFortran</title>
      <link>https://ondrejcertik.com/projects/contributions/lfortran/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ondrejcertik.com/projects/contributions/lfortran/</guid>
      <description>LFortran is a modern open-source (BSD licensed) interactive Fortran compiler built on top of LLVM. It can execute user&amp;rsquo;s code interactively to allow exploratory work (much like Python, MATLAB or Julia) as well as compile to binaries with the goal to run user&amp;rsquo;s code on modern architectures such as multi-core CPUs and GPUs.
Ondřej started the project in 2017, and is working towards getting first users and developers. He plans to make it a successful open source projects just like SymPy or SymEngine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fortran 90 Webpage</title>
      <link>https://ondrejcertik.com/projects/contributions/fortran90/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ondrejcertik.com/projects/contributions/fortran90/</guid>
      <description> Fortran 90 is a website which lists recommended practices for modern Fortran. It also has a section about side by side comparison with Python and an FAQ about Fortran. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resurrecting Fortran</title>
      <link>https://ondrejcertik.com/blog/2021/03/resurrecting-fortran/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ondrejcertik.com/blog/2021/03/resurrecting-fortran/</guid>
      <description>We have finished the first chapter on a long journey of resurrecting Fortran: forming an initial core community of developers and users with enough momentum around the new Fortran website and projects at fortran-lang.org. There is still have a long way to go to, but this was a necessary (although not sufficient) achievement and I feel this was a once in a life time event. The timing was right, we were ready, and we also got lucky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running for WG5 Convenor Announcement</title>
      <link>https://ondrejcertik.com/blog/2020/04/running-for-wg5-convenor-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ondrejcertik.com/blog/2020/04/running-for-wg5-convenor-announcement/</guid>
      <description>I decided to run for WG5 Convenor (International Fortran Committee Chair). I have written up a Platform document that explains why I am running, the issues as I see them, and how I propose to work with the Committee to address them (see also my CV). I have developed this platform with many Fortran community members, both inside and outside of the Fortran Committee. Furthermore, I have also posted the platform as a GitHub repository and I encourage anyone to open issues and Pull Requests (PRs) to discuss and further refine the platform.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>